Nicholas Dobner

A Brooklyn, NY

【● (484)-620-4253 | ■ dobner.nicholas@gmail.com | ② mintchkin | 🛅 nickdobner

CAREER OBJECTIVE

A senior or staff engineer role at a company that values mentorship and technical innovation, and can offer opportunities for growth to an experienced and motivated engineer with a diverse skillset and strong technical background.

ENGINEERING SKILLS

Languages: PYTHON, TYPESCRIPT, C#, ELM

Web: REACT, GRAPHQL, DJANGO, ASP.NET

Misc: GRPC, GIT, DOCKER, LATEX

WORK EXPERIENCE

2022 – Present Technologies

Staff Engineer at REPEATMD

Brooklyn, NY

TYPESCRIPT, C#, REACT, ASP.NET, AWS

Team lead of 6 other engineers building and maintaining an admin portal to manage a multi-tenant e-commerce platform

Redesign a payment processor backed by Stripe to support subscription and order management features through a custom webhook system

Develop an internal TypeScript SDK for our own REST API that featured automatic end-to-end type generation sourced from our OpenAPI spec

Start a tech "book" club, where the format is to watch a new tech conference talk each week and then lead other engineers in a discussion about the topic

2019 – 2022 TECHNOLOGIES

Senior Software Engineer at JOOR

Philadelphia, PA

PYTHON, TYPESCRIPT, GRPC, GRAPHQL, REACT, DJANGO

Team lead on a project for implementing real-time collaboration features and event streaming with kafka/debezium

Execute a large scale migration for existing GraphQL server application from JavaScript to TypeScript, including code generation and build configuration

Introduce engineering tooling improvements: a python formatter (black), a python build script manager (tox), and end-to-end type generation (mypy, typescript)

2018 – 2019 Technologies

Software Developer at JETSPRING, LLC.

Radnor, PA

PYTHON, C#, FLASK, ASP.NET

Replace legacy deployment system with automated Docker container deployments Project lead on a Flask web application for mass text message marketing campaigns

EDUCATION

2013 – 2015 2009 – 2012 Computer Science at Temple University

Philadelphia, PA

Piano Performance at CLEVELAND INSTITUTE OF MUSIC

Cleveland, OH

ADDITIONAL PROJECTS

Complete

Elmufactoria – A logic game for the browser about guiding robots from one end to the other, but only if they follow the rules!